我们让你在上一个问题中制造一个错误并修正它的原因
The reason why we asked you the last question about creating an error and
是这对于开发者来说是一个重要技能
fixing the error is because an important skill of developers
那就是修正错误
is to be able to get past errors.
没有一个开发者能够在第一次就写出完美无缺的代码
There's no developer who writes code perfectly the first time.
仔细想一想
If you think about it,
所有的 Google 搜索服务产品都不是在一天里写成的
the whole Google search product was not written in one day perfectly.
它需要需多年的反复修改 以前如此 以后仍然如此
It was a lot of iteration over many years, and it continues to be.
因此 无论你是一个新手开发者或有经验的开发者
So, regardless of whether you're a new developer or you're an experienced
完成目标并不是一帆风顺的
developer, in order to get to the end goal, it's not exactly a straight path.
你会在途中遇到各种各样的障碍 你得在其中展示出创造性
You'll run into obstacles along the way, and you have to be really creative in
以克服这些困难
terms of trying to come up with other solutions to go around that obstacle.
一旦你克服了 你会遇到另外的障碍 如此这般
So once you get around it, then you'll run into another obstacle and so on.
你会一直思索解决问题
And you just always want to keep thinking of ways to get
的方法
around that obstacle.
最终 你找到了一条到达目标的路径
And eventually, after a lot of work, you finally find the path to the goal, and
尽管历经坎坷 这仍然是物超所值的
even though it was super challenging, it was totally worth it in the end because
你会信心百倍并为你完成的工作而自豪
you feel empowered and confident and just really proud of your work.
真正优秀的开发者知道如何从错误中学习
So the really good developers know how to rebound from an error and
并继续他们的工作
continue with their work.
这些是一些用于调试、解决错误的
So here are some habits and
习惯和策略
strategies that they use to debug, or fix, their errors.
首先阅读错误信息
First they read the error message.
当你在 Google Docs 中写文档时
When you're writing a document in Google Docs, for example,
如果有拼写错误 它会用红色下划线提示
if there's any misspellings, then it will tell you with a red underline.
相似地 在Android Studio里 如果你写错了XML
Similarly in Android Studio, if you have typed XML incorrectly, then
会有一条红色下划波浪线 或者错误会被标红
it will have a red, squiggly underline, or it will be highlighted in red.
而且在这边的边栏
Also, in this bar on the side here,
如果你放在红色柱条上它会给你显示信息
it will show you the message if you hover over the red bar.
在我们的XML可视化器里面 也会有有帮助的错误信息
But in our XML Visualizer, there's also helpful error messages.
因此当我们制造一个错误的时候 比如说移除这个引号
So if I create an error, like removing this quotation mark, it will tell me
它会告诉我引号没有配对 我需要修正
that there's an uneven number of quotes and that I need to fix it.
有时 它也会告诉你出现问题所在的行
Sometimes, it also tells you the line number that the problem is on.
行号在左手边
The line numbers are on the left hand side here.
在第六行我们知道有一个问题
So, on line six, we know that there's a problem.
这有助于我们精确定位错误所在位置而非通读全部代码
This helps narrow down the problem space instead of having to read through all
才得以搞清楚错误
your code and trying to figure out what the problem is.
如果你仍然不知道错误信息
If you still don't understand the error message, try to
试图找出你知道意思的词和你不知道意思的词
identify words that you do understand and the words that you don't understand.
你可以 Google 你不知道意思的词
You can always Google search for the words that you don't understand, or you
或者直接把错误信息贴在 google 里搜
can just copy the whole error message and paste that into a Google search.
另一个技巧就是使用可以正常运行的样例代码
The other technique is to use working code samples and
并与你的代码比较 看看哪里有问题
compare it to what you have to try to figure out what went wrong.
我们已经在先前几个视频中给你了一些代码
We've already given you some code to look at in the last few videos, and
还有一个好的资源是常见Android View速查表
another good resource is the Common Android Views cheat sheet that
我们会把它给你
we'll provide you.
这里 我们会看到不同的 view 的名字和代码片段
Here, we see the names of different views, and we also have code snippets as
还有它们在设备上的预览
well as a preview of what they would look like on the device.
You can always compare your code to what we have here and
see if there's any differences.
The third technique is to use undo.
If you're paying attention when you type,
you should be able to see pretty quickly when you type something wrong.
Try undoing the last few keystrokes to see if any of those fixed the error.
As we showed you before, you can hit Cmd+Z to undo a change or
Cmd+Shift+Z to redo a change.
On Windows, it's Ctrl+Z to undo and Ctrl+Shift+Z to redo.
Or in the XML visualizer, we have these nice handy buttons for undo and redo.
If you really don't know what to do, you can always hit this Reset Code button,
which brings you back to the original code that we gave you,
which should work.
The fourth technique is to just ask for help.
You can reach out to other students on the peer chat in the lesson or
on the forums.
Oftentimes, just talking to another person will
help you work out your errors.
Don't be afraid to ask for help.
There's a lot of really nice Android developers out in the community who
are willing to help you.
In fact, being able to ask for help is an important skill for developers.
There are no bad questions.
The more you practice the better you'll be at knowing who to ask and
what to ask them in order to help you get to your answer faster.
You can also take a screenshot of the work that you're doing, whether it's
on the phone or in the XML Visualizer, and share that along with the code
on the forums or in chat so that people know the context in which you're asking.
Check out the instructor notes for more details.
Okay, so here's a chance for you to practice some of those techniques.
I have some code here that has errors.
If you click on the link below, it will bring you to the XML Visualizer
with this code already populated in there.
There's a bunch of error messages, so I want you to try to read them and
try to resolve the errors.
Then come back and describe at least two problems that you saw.
For extra credit, tell me if you discovered all four problems.